XIAOYU A. GAO

13107 Meadow Hall Court, Herndon VA, 20171 | (703) 901-0568 | gao_xiaoyu@bah.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack Javascript Developer with a passion for technology and innovation. My experience and expertise ranges from designing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures using Agile development methodologies. In particular, I specialize in web technologies such as React/Redux, Node.js/Express, Docker, Terraform and AWS.

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

- Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering
- Rodman Scholar (Honors Program for Top 5% of Engineers

Skills

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7), Shell (Bash), Java (7/8), C/C++

Front-End Web Technologies:

 HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, Ember, Handlebars, Bootstrap, PostCSS, CSSNext, CSS Modules, Webpack

Development Tools:

 Agile (Scrum), Git, Atom, Emacs, Eclipse, Intellij, Sketch, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, ESLint, NPM, Yarn

Operating Systems:

 Unix/Linux (Ubuntu 12.04+, Amazon Linux 2017+), Mac OS X (10.10+)

Back-End Web Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, Spring, MySQL, MongoDB

Infrastructure/Automation Technologies:

• Nginx, Apache2, Docker, Travis, Terraform, Packer, AWS

Work Experience

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - Present

- Currently working towards an Associate AWS Certified Solutions Architect Certification.
- · Completed Ember training on Code School.

Capital One - Technology Development Intern

June 2015 - August 2015

- Developed a sprint tracking web application that aggregates data from various tools such as VersionOne, Git/SVN, Hudson/Jenkin and SonarCubed in an user-friendly and responsive dashboard interface.
- Aided in the design of the UX/UI and implemented front-end logic to display data to users as well as validate inputs using AngularJS, Jquery, SASS and custom CSS.
- Developed RESTful APIs to allow communication between front-end and back-end using Spring Core.
- Deployed application to an internally accessible AWS server.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Research Assistant Intern

May 2014 - August 2014

- Developed an email filtration IDS web application for detecting malicious email content.
- Application performed full packet capture of SMTP traffic and static analysis of email pcaps and links using Bro-IDS & MASTIFF.
- Designed front-end interface using Jquery and Bootstrap and developed the back-end with Flask and SQLAlchemy.
- Application used to collect metrics on email traffic to improve incident response time for internal cyber security team.

Select Projects

Mogura Miner (github.com/MoguraMiner)

- An AWS-based cloud mining operation using a EC2 Spot Fleet to mine cryptocurrency via a central master node running on a separate on demand instance.
- A dockerized Node application runs regular calculations to automatically update the bid price on the Spot Fleet.
- AMIs for the Spot Fleet and the primary on demand instance are created with Packer and the cloud infrastructure is provisioned and configured with Terraform.

UVA Lambdas Website (github.com/UVA-Lambdas)

- The official home page of Lambda Phi Epsilon, Alpha Tau Chapter, at the University of Virginia.
- Designed in Sketch, written as an SPA with React and styled with CSS4 using PostCSS and CSSNext.
- Automated deployment to Github pages using Travis for CI/CD.